We can now start our Q&A session.
OK.
Kin is always the first one.
(Laughter)
I always begin the first question.
OK. You talk about the ecological crisis.
OK.
For us Chinese people,
I think our culture tend to treat the other world,
non-human world as object of consumption.
So we eat shark fin, you know,
and we eat abalone,
and we eat everything, OK?
Everything edible to Chinese people.
So it's a reflection that we consume
the non-human world for our benefit.
That's part of our culture.
So in this context,
how do you talk to non-Christian
about, you know, the community of life
that, you know, the shark fish is part of our life,
the abalone is part of our life.
How do you communicate this to the general public?
You know, what's your suggestion?
(Laughter)
(Clears throat)
May we first thank Dr. Hong Liang.
I trusted him without understanding.
(Laughter)
I think the ecological crisis
affects every human being on earth.
And therefore,
planetary solidarity is in hand
and is for everybody understandable
for meeting this danger.
The danger is universal
and every human being
has a duty to save life.
(Clears throat)
We have the order of God, human beings, the earth.
And the Tao Te Ching of Chinese wisdom,
we have the order of the divine, the earth,
than the human being.
And we have to learn Chinese wisdom of Lao Tse
to respect the earth as our mother.
Tao Te Ching second part.
OK.
(Silence)
This is a question sheet from...
(Chinese)
An old confession of the Orthodox Church in Aquileia, Italy.
It says to Christ,
(Chinese)
I had an experience in my desperation
behind barbed wire in the prison camps after the war.
And with Christ, the suffering Christ,
what I not have hope and a years to life
in this dangerous situation.
(Silence)
(Chinese)
She would like to know the genetically modified food
and how would it...
The GM food, the genetically modified food,
how does it related to the ecological crisis?
Do you have any comments on the...
Do you understand the genetically modified GM food?
(Silence)
I am for natural food and not for artificial food.
And my grandsons are vegan.
(Chinese)
(Laughter)
我想問一問,
剛才你說人類中心是其中一個問題,
其中一個對於自然環境是一個經濟危機,
人類中心可能是之前卡爾巴克的問題,
如果是這樣,
我們作為人類,
你最後問的問題,
究竟我們是否應該是,
或者不是,
還有這件事是否無論是Sherry也好,
Lobby也好,
是否可能,
還有怎樣可以成為可能?
(Chinese)
(English)
天、夜、光芒、創造的天皇是第七天的食糧
這就是著名的考察問題:基督是否根據基督的說法在六天或七天內創造了世界呢?
(回答:回答給自己)
(笑)
(這位先生:我會想問一個問題,關於時間的概念)
(這位先生:我知道您在您的《希望的道理》中提到基督是根據基督的說法)
(這位先生:您提出我們應該以循環的時間來取代現代的概念)
(這位先生:您如何解釋您對於時間的看法?)
(回答:您每年慶祝生日,我越來越老了)
(回答:所以,生日的循環是在一個時間線上)
(回答:時間的循環是在一個時間線上)
(回答:我們正在朝著未來的方向)
(這位先生:這兩個問題是關於經濟的,我可以將它們結合並向您介紹)
(這位先生:您提到社會正義是一個非常重要的問題)
(這位先生:如果我們要解決社會正義,貧困問題,我們應該透過公共管理來解決問題)
(這位先生:您如何建議我們如何幫助解決社會正義)
(這位先生:我們可以從我們的位置開始,以及我們有的社會角色,或是我們可以做一些政治和政治的事情)
(這位先生:您可以更詳細地解釋我們可以做的事嗎?)
(回答:我可以更詳細地解釋我們可以做的事嗎?)
(這位先生:我們可以更詳細地解釋我們可以做的事嗎?)
(這位先生:在提出其他問題之前)
(這位先生:我想提醒那些在Dossett的學校)
(這位先生:因為我們的助手需要收集資料)
(這位先生:所以這將是最後一堆問題)
(這位先生:這兩條問題是關於科技)
(這位先生:我們如何處理)
第二個問題
我已經回答了
聰明的人學習在內
聰明的人學習在外
在大浪中
(你對這方面有什麼意見?)
我對這方面有什麼意見?
我希望,但不太有信心
因為我是一個貪心的人
我也是一個有信心的人
(笑)
有信心和貪心
沒有分別去處理未來
(這兩個問題是關於現代的個人主義)
(第一)
(在一個極度個人主義的自由社會)
(我們面臨著嚴重的社會崩潰)
(我們如何應對)
(以及營造社會的協調)
(為一個正義和關心的社會)
(第二)
(在現代世界)
(有強烈的強調)
(追求個人的快樂和個人的身份)
(例如)
(社會主義)
(他們也聲稱)
(正面宣揚生活)
(有許多種類)
(社會主義的社會主義)
(我們作為基督徒)
(如何看待這些社會主義?)
(請尊重自己的選擇)
(這是基督徒Paul的建議)
(但我沒有回答)
(這是最後一個問題)
(說「對」生活可能勇敢)
(但有時也可能不公平)
(當一個人身體受到極度的痛苦)
(而生活沒有正義)
(你認為自殺是否有幫助)
(這對某些人來說)
(可能會更加有價值)
(高齡的人)
(他們有百分之百的)
(希望健康的疾病)
(讓他們選擇去瑞士)
(自殺)
(我不會指責他們)
(但對我來說)
(這從來不是問題)
(兩年前)
(我太太因癌症死亡)
(我們沒有討論自殺)
(謝謝莫子曼教授)
(謝謝大家)
(感謝)
謝謝大家